本字幕首发于字幕组网站
www.ZiMuZu.tv 欢迎交流
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
翻译：草草  feilixiaozi  CS漫画家小明  潇湘月影  香茗小焙  木浅薰
翻译：王大可  某羽  鱼小姐  杨一勾校对：油炸电风扇   潇湘月影
时间轴：Spohy    永远的永远
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第五季   第一集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
你是我见过的最出色的女人
You're the most amazing woman I have ever met.
你是在做我认为你在做的那件事吗
Are you doing what I think you're doing?
瑞秋・伊丽莎白・赞恩
Rachel Elizabeth Zane...
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
-愿意  -愿意吗
- Yes. - Yes?
你想把迈克从我身边夺走
You want my permission to take Mike
然后强迫他做你的助理
and force him to be your associate.
要么现在说  要么永远别出声
Speak now, or forever hold your peace.
我给咱俩弄了点东西
I got us something.
正好配我们的完美联手
The perfect way to consummate our relationship.
-等我一下  我去厨房拿  -好的
- So just wait right here. It's in the kitchen. - Sure.
我可不能放任你这么做
I can't let you do this.
你只是回到你本来的家
You're going back where you belong.
你从来不关心我
You never cared about me.
你只关心你自己
All you care about is yourself.
路易  我不是诺玛
Louis, I'm not Norma.
我说过不会让你出事
I told you I'd never let anything happen to you,
就绝对会遵守诺言
and I won't ever.
我该走了
I should go.
为什么
Why?
你知道我爱你  唐娜
You know I love you, Donna.
在你告诉我你爱我之后就跑掉了
You ran away, but not before you told me you loved me.
我之所以那么说是为了让你好受点
I did that because I wanted to make you feel better.
我不需要你的怜悯
I don't want your pity.
你得开始想着找新秘书了
You need to start thinking about a new secretary.
哈维根本不知道拥有你是多幸运的一件事
Harvey has no idea how lucky he is to have you.
我要离开你了  哈维
I'm leaving you, Harvey.
不能就这样辞职
You can't just quit.
我不是要辞职
I'm not quitting.
我要去为路易工作
I'm going to work for Louis.
我告诉他  律师费的事我可以让步
So I told him I'll cave on the billables,
但如果他要个成天巴结他的人
but if he wants someone to kiss his ass all day,
他得去找路易
he'll have to settle for Louis.
那他怎么说
And what did he say?
不知道  但我们拿到了钱
I don't know, but we got paid
他一周也没来烦我了
and I haven't heard from him in a week.
我得说  哈维  总体看来
I have to say Harvey, all things considered,
你对唐娜去为路易工作这件事还挺豁达的
you're taking this whole Donna-Louis thing in stride.
我虽然也有困难  但那只会让我更坚强
Well, I may have my issues, but they only make me stronger.
很好  因为我们马上要走进一间
Good, because we're about to walk into a room
坐满自以为掐着我们命脉的人的屋子了
packed with people who think they've got us by the balls.
我才不管他们怎么想呢
Well, I don't care what they think,
我一定会大杀四方
cause I'm gonna kill it.
怎么回事
What the hell's going on?
情况就是  我给你留了五通留言
What's going on is I left you five messages
你却没回话
and you never called me back.
会议一小时前就结束了  而你们不在
The meeting was over an hour ago and you weren't here.
五通留言
Five messages?
请你理解  我的秘书走了
Please, you have to understand, I lost my secretary.
我才不管  我的公司都丢了
I don't give a shit. I lost my company.
不  还没有
No, you haven't.
我们能拿回来的
We can get them back.
我可以解决
I can take care of it.
扯淡
Bullshit.
你连自己的事都解决不了
You can't even take care of yourself.
抱歉  哈维  你只能靠自己了
Sorry, Harvey. You're on your own.
然后呢
And then what happens?
然后我醒了
And then I get up.
你醒来之后是什么感觉
And how do you feel when you get up?
我说了  我不想谈感受
I told you I don't wanna talk about how I feel.
那你为什么来呢
Then what are you doing here?
这你清楚
You know what I'm doing here.
我说了  你要想治好失眠
I told you, your sleepless nights aren't going to stop
就必须接受
until you accept the fact that your secretary
你的秘书不会再回来这个事实
isn't coming back.
我也说了  等她回来了  我就不会再失眠了
And I told you they'll stop when she does.
再给我写个处方
So just write me another prescription
让我在那之前能睡个安稳觉
and let me get some sleep in the meantime.
那样是不行的
It doesn't work that way.
那要怎么才行
Then how does it work?
你先跟我说说
Why don't we start with you taking me
到底怎么回事吧
through the whole story again?
那有什么用
What the hell good is that gonna do?
你想听真话吗
You want the truth?
我觉得你可能有所隐瞒
I think you might have left some things out.
我没有  我也不会
Well, I didn't, and I'm not about to
再回顾那点烂事了
go through this whole damn thing again.
那就另找个医生吧
Then go and find yourself another doctor.
你不跟我开口  我是不会
Because I'm not writing a prescription for anything
给你写处方的
without you talking to me.
六周前
我就是忍不住不盯着它看
I...I can't stop staring at it.
我发现了
Oh, I noticed.
嗯  其他人也会发现的
Yeah. So will everyone else.
是啊  要的不就这效果吗
Well, I mean, yeah, that's the point.
让大家知道你属于我了
For everyone to realize that you're my property.
好吧
Okay.
我现在归你了吗
Are you saying you own me now?
当然  这个
Oh, hell yeah, and this here
就是你手指的项圈
is just like a little collar for your finger.
迈克  说真的
Mike, seriously...
我们昨晚告诉我父母了
I know we told my parents last night,
但我在考虑  律所方面
but I was thinking that, in terms of work,
或许我们暂时还是别说出去
maybe we should keep it to ourselves for a bit.
我明白
I understand.
-真的  -嗯
- You do? - Sure.
我们身边像是有一个泡泡
You know, it's like there's this bubble around us,
你暂时还不想戳破
and you just don't want it to burst yet.
你不介意吗
And you're okay with that?
瑞秋  你刚刚答应跟我共度余生
Rachel, you just agreed to spend the rest of your life with me.
现在  我什么都不介意
Right now I'm pretty okay with everything.
那就说定了
Then it's settled.
我们就只告诉唐娜
We'll tell Donna and that's it.
什么
What?
那个泡泡呢  唐娜不在泡泡里啊
What about the bubble? There's no Donna in the bubble.
得了  唐娜当然在泡泡里
Come on, there's room for Donna in the bubble.
你知道我可以
You realize I get to sleep with
跟泡泡里的人上床吧
whoever's in the bubble, right?
你知道我爸爸也在泡泡里吧
So long as you realize that my dad's in the bubble.
那就告诉唐娜
Donna it is.
过来  好了
Come here. All right.
记得网上那个吗
Remember that thing online?
我们要实行一下
We're doing it.
唐娜  你干什么呢
Donna, what the hell are you doing?
你觉得呢
What does it look like I'm doing?
丢掉这些简历
I'm getting rid of these résumés.
天呐  女人  你疯了吗
No, no. Oh, my God, woman, are you crazy?
我十分钟后要见诺玛的接替者
I have interviews with Norma's replacements in ten minutes.
这要麻烦了  因为
Oh, that's gonna be hard considering the fact
我取消了你所有的会面
that I canceled all your interviews.
该死的  唐娜
Damn it, Donna,
那都是本市最佳的应聘者
those were the best candidates in the city.
不  路易  本市最佳的应聘者
No, Louis, the best candidate in the city
就站在你面前
is standing right in front of you.
但你拒绝我了啊
But you told me no.
现在我答应你了
And now I'm saying yes.
这是我这辈子最棒的时刻
This is the most amazing moment in my entire life.
很好
Good.
这两周我会给你找个临时工
I'll get you a temp for a couple of weeks
然后我们就正式开始
and then we'll get started.
等等  对不起  等等
Wait, I'm sorry, wait.
你还没告诉哈维吗
You haven't told Harvey yet?
我告诉他了  但我得给他两周时间
I told him. I just-- I have to give him two weeks.
好吧  你知道吗  我又想了一下
Okay, you know what, on second thought,
虽然我非常感激你的好意
as much as I appreciate the gesture,
我认为你还是应该和哈维在一起
I think you should just stay with Harvey.
你说什么呢  这不是什么好意
What are you talking about? This isn't a gesture.
不  听着
No, look, you just--
你记得之前迈克差点成为我的助理律师吗
Do you remember Mike almost became my associate?
我说什么呢  你当然记得
What am I talking about? Of course you do.
那你一定也记得
Well then, you'll also remember that
迈克刚刚答应了我
just as Mike had said yes,
哈维就搅了进来
Harvey swoops in
在最后一秒钟把他抢了回去
and he takes him back from me at the last second.
不会发生那种事的
That isn't gonna happen.
你不知道的是我离开了办公室
What you don't know is that I left the room.
我去给迈克拿了个蛋糕
I went to get Mike this cake that said,
上面写着"欢迎来到利特团队"
"Welcome to Team Litt."
等我两分钟后回来的时候
Two minutes later, I come back and there they are,
他们两个就在击掌  欢笑  然后一起走了
high-fiving, laughing, and then they leave.
我就把蛋糕扔了
I threw the cake out.
我不能接受你再做一次那样的事
I cannot have that happen again with you.
路易  我说了不会再发生那种事了
Louis, I told you that isn't gonna happen.
你没听到我的话吗
Did you not just hear me?
哈维只用了两分钟就把迈克抢回去了
It took Harvey two minutes to steal Mike back from me.
在你这儿  他有两周时间
With you, he has two weeks.
所以还是不用了
So no thank you.
唐娜  我需要在午餐之前联系上亨德森
Donna, I need to get in touch with Henderson before lunch,
我还要给布拉克斯顿准备一瓶红酒
And I need to get Braxton a bottle of wine.
都办完了
I took care of all that.
好的  谢谢
Good. Thanks.
你还有什么想说的吗
Is there anything else you want to talk about?
我想不到什么了
Not that I can think of.
你真的认为只要你装作我该主意了
Did you really think that if you just
我就真的会改主意吗
acted like I changed my mind that I'd change my mind?
得了吧  唐娜  路易
Oh, come on, Donna, Louis?
你觉得你俩能维持多久
I mean, how long do you think that's going to last?
我想维持多久就多久
It's gonna last however long I want it to last.
-唐娜  -哈维  这件事已经定了
- Donna-- - Harvey, this is happening.
这是给你的正式通知
This is my formal notice.
但我不会立刻把你晾下
But I have no intention of leaving you high and dry,
所以我们还是讨论一下
so let's talk about finding you
在两周内为你找一个新秘书吧
someone in the next two weeks.
-找个新秘书  -是的
- Finding me someone? - Yes.
我已经准备了一份市里最优秀法务秘书的名单
I already have a list of the top legal secretaries in the city.
你是说在你决定抛弃我之前
You mean you made a list for Louis
为路易准备的那份名单吗
before you decided to abandon me?
我没有抛弃你  哈维
I'm not abandoning you, Harvey.
我是为了自己着想
I'm doing what's best for me.
既然我们都在为自己着想
Well, as long as we're doing what's best for ourselves,
那你知道怎样对我最好吗
you know what's best for me?
直面伤痛
Ripping the Band-Aid off.
-哈维  -所以你还是赶快
- Harvey-- - So why don't you clean out
收拾你的东西搬去路易那里吧
your desk, walk yourself over to Louis,
顺便带上你的名单
and take that with you?
这不是两个互相在意的成年人向前看的方法
This isn't how two adults who care about each other move on.
在我看来  两个互相在意的成年人
As far as I'm concerned, two adults who
根本不用向前看
care about each other don't move on at all.
所以如果你要走  那就走吧
So, if you're gonna go, just go.
你在这干什么呢
What the hell are you doing in here?
凯文・斯莱特里已经等了20分钟了
Kevin Slattery's been waiting 20 minutes.
-什么  -凯文・斯莱特里
- What? - Kevin Slattery.
唐娜没告诉你吗
Didn't Donna tell you?
没有  她
No, she, um--
哈维  到底怎么了
Harvey, what's going on?
没怎么
Nothing's going on.
凯文・斯莱特里来这里干什么
Why is Kevin Slattery here?
他在找新律师
He's looking for a new lawyer,
我想让你去搞定他
and I'm looking for you to close him.
-为什么是我  -为什么不是你
- Why me? - Why not you?
因为全世界都知道
Because everybody and their mother knows
他们两周内就会破产
they're going bankrupt in two weeks
但我不是破产方面的专家
and I'm not a bankruptcy expert.
你在听我说话吗
Aren't you listening to me?
他不想宣布破产
He doesn't want to declare bankruptcy.
他想让你为他尽力一争
He wants you to fight for him.
那他今天可是来对了
Then he's come to me on the right day.
凯文  我听说你想打场硬仗
Kevin, I hear you're looking for a fight
我也知道我们的时间不多了
and I understand we don't have much time.
确实  但我刚浪费了半个小时等你
We don't, and I just wasted half an hour waiting for you.
所以在正式合作之前  你需要说服我
So, before we get to anything, you're gonna convince me
我为什么要和你合作
why I should go with you in the first place.
好吧  那我们没得谈了
Okay, we're done.
出去的时候别撞到门
Don't let the door hit you on the way out.
-什么  -你听到我的话了
- What? - You heard me.
我们之中只有一个人面临破产  而那不是我
Only one of us is facing bankruptcy and it isn't me.
所以比起责骂我迟到
So instead of scolding me for being late,
你更需要说服我
you needed to be convincing me
为什么我要拯救你那濒死的公司
why I should save your dying company.
很高兴见到你
So, nice to meet you.
忠诚
Loyalty.
你刚说什么
What did you just say?
我现在有个能改变局面的合同
I have a game-changing contract that's guaranteed
只要我们能证明有偿付能力  六周内一定能拿到
to come my way in six weeks if we can show solvency.
谁来保证能拿到
Guaranteed by who?
我的大学室友
My college roommate.
你把这事告诉了你的银行家们
And you tell that to your bankers,
消息传出去了  有人来争
word gets out it's up for bid,
你的竞争对手出低价压制你
your competitors undercut you,
你的室友就帮不上你了
and your roommate won't be able to help you anymore.
但如果能撑六周  就能有转机
But if we make it six weeks, we're back in business.
我保证绝不抛弃你
And I guarantee we'll never leave you.
事情是这样的  凯文
Here's the thing, Kevin.
我才不在乎一家只能让我们的营业额
I don't give a shit about a regional trucking company
增加1%的地区货运公司
that's only going to increase our billings 1%.
我帮你起死回生
I get you out of this,
你们的股票肯定一路疯涨
your stock's gonna go through the roof.
-你想入股  -我要20%
- You want a piece. - I want 20%.
没门
No way.
别忘了  是你来找的我
You're the one coming to me. Okay?
握住80%总比一无所有强
80% of something is a whole lot better than 100% of nothing.
你对外也能像现在这么厉害吗
You gonna fight out there like you just did in here?
这只是赛前热身  凯文
This is the preseason, Kevin.
我连汗都没出呢
I haven't even broken a sweat.
有空吗
Do you have a second?
有  怎么了
Yeah, sure. What's going on?
唐娜  你在发抖吗
Donna, are you shaking?
我就不该期望...他能...
I never should have - expected him to--
出什么事了
What's going on?
没事  别在意  抱歉
You know what? Never mind. Sorry.
你想说什么
What did you want to talk about?
你不该期望谁怎么样
You never should've expected who to what?
出什么事了
What happened?
我要离开哈维
I'm leaving Harvey.
天哪
Oh, my God.
为什么
Why?
还记得我跟你说你再也回不了头了
You remember when I told you you could never go back,
然后我说我在撒谎吗
and then I said I lied about that?
结果发现我说自己在撒谎就是个谎言
Turns out I was lying when I said I lied.
所以你就要离开吗
So you're just gonna leave?
我不走  我去帮路易
No, I'm going to work for Louis.
什么  什么时候开始
What? When?
今天
Today.
对不起  瑞秋
I'm sorry, Rachel.
你不是来找我说这个的
You didn't come in here to talk about this.
-你想跟我说什么  -没事
- What did you wanna talk-- - No.
没什么
It's nothing.
不着急
It can wait.
-有东西要给我吗  -我什么时候空手过
- You got something for me? - When don't I?
我重写了你那个撤销科特案的烂动议
I redid your shitty motion to dismiss on Colter.
我的烂动议
My shitty motion?
你提到的那个判例就跟
Yeah, your precedents might as well have been
火石跟硬汉[摩登原始人主角]的关系
Flintstone v. Rubble.
《摩登原始人》是经典象征
Listen to me, The Flintstones is an iconic classic
能清晰的传达出一个事实
that clearly conveys the fact--
-你很老的事实吗  -这可是你
- That you're old? - Hey, you're the one
先提起那部动画的
who came up with the reference.
这传达出我很聪明的事实
Which conveys the fact that I'm smart.
今早有人用了自信爆棚
Wow, somebody took their confidence booster shot
-加速器啊  -其实  我是昨晚用的
- this morning. - Actually, I took it last night.
这个加速器就是我向瑞秋求婚了
And by took it, I mean I asked Rachel to marry me.
见鬼  我不该告诉你这个的
Oh shit, I wasn't supposed to tell you that,
但我说漏嘴了
but I just did.
那我先不祝贺你了
Then I won't say congratulations yet.
不  你还是可以祝贺的
Oh, no, you can still say it.
我也可以让你列出
I can also say I need a list
斯莱特里公司所有债权人的名单
of every one of Slattery Corp's creditors,
我昨天就要了
and I need it yesterday.
你为什么说这个而不是祝贺我
Now, why would you say that instead of congratulations?
因为我们只有不到两周时间
Because we have less than two weeks
阻止他们破产
to keep them out of bankruptcy
要做到这一点  就要知道凯文・斯莱特里
and we can't do that without knowing every person
究竟都欠谁的钱
Kevin Slattery owes a nickel to.
哈维  那估计得有五十多个人
Harvey, that list is gonna be over 50 names long.
两周之内不可能全都说服
There's no way we can get to all of them in two weeks.
与其告诉我做不到什么
You know what? Instead of telling me what we can't do
还管我要《新娘》杂志
and asking me for a copy of Brides Magazine,
你不如赶紧去把名单列好
why don't you just get the damn list together?
我们订婚的事你告诉他了
You told him we're engaged?
我没忍住  但现在我后悔了
I couldn't help myself. But I wish I hadn't told him.
哈维  出什么事了
Harvey, what's going on with you?
没事
Nothing's going on.
恭喜你们  好了  我说了
Congratulations. There, I said it.
我的日程表呢
Where the hell is my calendar?
昨天就在桌上
You know, I had it right here yesterday.
我不知道  我去叫唐娜
I don't know. I'll go get Donna.
不  别叫唐娜  我自己找
No, don't get Donna. I'll take care of it.
别叫唐娜是什么意思
What do you mean don't get Donna?
我说了我自己找
I said I'll take care of it.
我找到了
I've got it right here.
谢谢  瑞秋
Thanks, Rachel.
这里是哈维・斯佩克特办公室
Harvey Specter's office.
他现在不在
No, he's not available right now.
需要留言吗
Can I take a message?
你为什么没告诉他唐娜的事
Why didn't you tell him about Donna?
因为我知道瑞秋知道  她会告诉他
Because I knew Rachel knew, and she'd tell him,
我就不需要浪费时间了
and then I wouldn't have to waste my time with it.
你是怕浪费时间还是怕有情绪
Waste time or feel something?
你觉得我不说就没有情绪了吗
You think I wasn't feeling something anyway?
你有什么情绪
And what were you feeling?
眼下  我感觉这个取证会
Right now, I'm feeling this deposition
-不会有尽头了  -这不是取证会
- is never going to end. - This isn't a deposition,
你也别想能轻易结束
and you're not getting out of this that easily.
我有点受够你这种态度了
You know what, I'm getting a little tired of your attitude.
什么态度
And what attitude is that?
你是指我拒绝为
The attitude where I'm not gonna supply
一个不肯向我说实话的人
prescription narcotics to someone
开麻醉药物吗
who won't tell me the truth?
是你那种一副比我自己还
The attitude that says you know me
了解我的态度
better than I know myself.
我没有说过我比你还了解你自己
I never said I know you better than you know yourself.
但你说我有事瞒着你
You said I'm keeping things from you.
你跟我一样清楚那就是事实
And that's something you know just as much as I do.
胡扯  我说的都是实话
Oh, bullshit. I've been telling the truth
我一句都没隐瞒全都告诉你了
this whole time and I haven't left out a goddamn word.
哈维  如果你非要这样
Okay, Harvey, if that's how you wanna play it.
那我就是比你了解你
I do know you better than you know yourself.
你进我门来四秒钟
I had you pegged about four seconds
我就看穿你了
after you walked in my door,
所以我知道杰西卡去找你时
which is why I know you weren't just
你不只是去洗脸了
washing your face when Jessica walked in.
你洗脸是因为你吐了
You were washing your face because you threw up.
你骗自己说是因为你病了
And you told yourself that you were coming down with something
或者吃坏东西了
or you had some bad clams.
但我来告诉你真相
But I'll tell you what really happened.
你吐了是因为你惊恐发作了
You threw up because you had a panic attack.
你来找我也不是
And you're not coming to me
因为你晚上睡不好觉
because you're having trouble sleeping.
你来找我是因为你害怕
You're coming to me because you're scared to death
这种事再次发生
that it'll happen again.
迈克  我能跟你谈谈吗
Mike, can I talk to you for a minute?
谈什么
What do you wanna talk about?
那位混蛋队长吗
Captain Dickhead back there?
我觉得我们现在不该对他这么苛刻
Look, I think maybe we should cut him a little slack.
他不知道我们订婚时
No, I cut him some slack when he
我就有放他一马
barely acknowledged our engagement.
然后我说要找唐娜来帮他
Then I tried to get Donna to help him
结果他要吃人一样
and he bites my head off.
干什么啊
What are you doing?
唐娜要离开他
Donna's leaving him.
还要去为路易工作
And she's going to work for Louis.
发生了什么
What the hell happened?
他们一起经历了那么多
They've been through everything together.
还有什么能
What could possibly--
天哪  他们越线了
Oh, my God, they crossed the line.
没那么简单
It's more complicated than that.
什么意思
What does that mean?
他们多年前就越线了
They crossed the line years ago.
那都无所谓了
You know what? It doesn't matter.
我也不想知道更多了  当然
I don't need to no anymore. Of course...
我们会尽量让着哈维的
we'll cut Harvey all the slack in the world.
我得晚点下班
Okay, I am going to stay late
帮他把事情整理好
and help him get everything in order.
但要记着
Hey, just keep in mind that
我让着他是一码事
cutting him some slack is one thing.
你去做唐娜的工作是另一码事
Doing Donna's job is another.
就一天
It's just one day.
又不是永远这样
It's not gonna last forever.
-你怎么知道我在这儿的  -很简单
- How'd you find me here? - Easy.
我知道今早那样吵架后  你肯定
I knew after this morning, you'd come in here
要来这里吃你的自怜三明治套餐
and your standard sandwich of commiseration.
我才没有什么自怜三明治套餐
I don't have a sandwich of commiseration--
黑麦面包  加培根不要俄式调味酱
Rueben on rye, with bacon instead of Russian dressing.
是全熟培根
Well-done bacon.
如果你不介意的话
And if it's all the same to you,
我喜欢一个人吃
I would prefer to eat by myself.
可以
Fine.
我只是来给你这个的
I just came in here to give you this.
皮尔逊・斯佩克特・利特
唐娜・鲍尔森
你是说
You mean...
从今天起我就开始为你工作
Today is the day I work for you.
天哪
Oh, my God.
我简直不敢相信  这是真的吗
I can't believe it. This is really happening?
我们先做什么
What do we do first?
我现在好激动
I mean, I'm so goddamn turned on right now.
不知道  也许可以开始着手
I don't know. Maybe we could get a jump on
解决诺玛留下的山一样的事情
some of the things that have been piling up since Norma.
我的录音笔都满了
Well, my Dictaphone's at full capacity,
都快溢出来了
it's about to burst.
我可以帮你解决这个问题
Well, I could help you with that.
-真的吗  -当然
- Would you? - Of course.
那就是我的工作嘛
That's my job.
处理录音笔里堆积的内容
Relieving the pressure on your Dictaphone.
其实  也许我们
Okay, you know what? Maybe we're, um...
进展太快了
moving too quickly.
好吧  要不然
Okay. Well, how about
我先重新梳理你的日程
I just redo your calendar,
把你的每个案子都加上索引
and index every live case you have, and then get to know
彻底摸清你的文件整理系统
every single inch of your filing system.
我觉得这进展一点也没比刚才慢
I don't think that's moving less quickly.
最终到达终将来到的那一刻
Culminating in that inevitable moment
当你的电话响起
when your phone finally rings
我将说出那个带有魔力的词
and I say those three magic words.
我的神啊
Oh, good sweet Jesus.
路易・利特办公室
"Louis Litt's office."
该死的  女人  我们现在就回去
God damn it, woman, we're going back right now.
你结账  小费给10%
Take care of the bill. 10% tip.
让全熟培根滚蛋吧
Well-done bacon, my ass.
他可没在想滚床单的事
He's totally not thinking about sex right now.
告诉我你找到了全部五十个债权人
Tell me you found all 50 creditors.
不只找全了五十个  我还找到了该找的那个
Not just all 50. I found the one.
你怎么知道你找到的是该找的
How do you know you found the right one?
因为我知道你会怎么做
Because I know exactly what you're gonna do.
那你来看看我要怎么做吧
Then let me show you how I'm gonna do it.
你真打算要求他们这么做吗
You're really gonna make them do that?
-当然  -所有人
- Sure am. - All of them?
有几个人不吃这套
Doesn't work with some of them.
北方还是南方
North or South?
随你挑
Take your pick.
哈维  这主意太棒了
Well, Harvey, that's brilliant.
只有一个问题  这么做是违法的
There's only one problem. It's illegal.
让他们告啊  这是民事案件  又不是刑事案件
Let 'em sue us. It's civil, not criminal.
反正我们就是要吓唬他们一下
Besides, we're bluffing anyway.
要是我告诉你  我可以让它变得合法呢
What if I told you I have a way to make it legal anyway?
那你的点子最好快点生效
I'd say your idea better work fast
因为我们一小时后就得过去
because we're going over there in an hour.
文斯・山菲利普
Vince Sanfillipo?
正是
Yes.
你不转过来是有什么特殊原因吗
Is there a reason you're not turning around?
我喜欢跟一些来访者玩点小游戏
I like to play a little game with some of my visitors.
比如说  你用依云护肤霜
For example, you use Evian skin cream
偶尔会喷比翼双飞香水
and sometimes you wear L'Air du Temps.
-但今天没有  -当然
- But not today. - Of course I do.
出自《沉默的羔羊》
我是南部白种穷鬼的后代
I'm just one generation away from poor white trash.
一心想着走出去
And I could only dream of getting out.
走去天涯海角
Getting anywhere.
直走到联邦调查局
Getting all the way to the FBI.
曾经有个人口调查员也这么诈我来着
A census taker tried to test me once.
我就着蚕豆和美味的基安蒂红葡萄酒
I ate his liver with some fava beans
把他的肝脏吃了
and a nice Chianti.
你很有观察力  医生  但你能否用
You see a lot, Doctor. But are you strong enough
-你敏锐的观察力...  -等价交换  克拉丽斯
- to point that high-powered-- - Quid pro quo, Clarice--
行了  够了
All right. That's enough.
我们不是来对台词的
We didn't come here for a quote-off.
当然不是
No, you didn't.
你们是来让我多给凯文・斯莱特里一点时间
You came here to get me to give Kevin Slattery more time,
而这是不可能的
and that's never going to happen.
事实上  我们是来让你
Actually, we're here to get you to
收购与斯莱特里货运有关的全部债务
buy up every piece of debt associated with Slattery Freight
然后说服你多给他一点时间
and then get you to give him more time.
我为什么要这么做
And why would I do that?
为什么  因为你是最大的债权人
Why? Because you're the biggest debtholder,
如果其他债权人提出索赔
and if any of the others makes a claim,
将会使之破产  而你得在五年之后
it'll trigger bankruptcy, and you get 50 cents
才能收回一美元债务里的五十美分
on the dollar five years from tomorrow.
你以为你们能引用《沉默的羔羊》的台词
You think I'm gonna double down on a loser,
我就会在失败者身上加注吗
because you can quote Silence of the Lambs?
不  你会这么做是因为
No, you're gonna do it
一旦我们申请破产
because the day we file bankruptcy,
运输队的货车会直接开去加拿大
every truck in that fleet's going straight to Canada.
到时五十美分就只剩二十五美分了
And that 50 cents on the dollar just hit 25.
这是违法的  我会告你
But that's illegal and I will sue you
把你和你的客户告到死
and your client into the ground.
如果我们没有用一美元买下
Well, it would be illegal
一个倒闭的加拿大汽车货运公司的话
if we hadn't just a bought a defunct
确实是违法的
Canadian trucking company for a dollar.
胡扯
Bullshit!
你们的合同条款不允许你们这么做
Your covenants prohibits you from doing that.
赶在有人申报债权前就没事
Not if we do it before anyone calls in our debt.
而我们已经买了
Which we did.
你个狗娘养的
You're a son of a bitch.
我想到这个主意的时候
That's exactly what I thought of myself
也是这么觉得的
when I came up with the idea.
说句公道话  加拿大汽车货运公司
To be fair, I was the one that came up with
这个点子是我想出来的
the defunct Canadian trucking company thingy.
-所以...  -对  没错
- So... - Oh, yeah, you're right.
你也是个狗娘养的
You're a son of a bitch, too.
谢了  哈维  感激不尽
Oh, thanks, Harvey. I appreciate that.
你说我们是狗娘养的我们也认了
Well, now that we agree what we are,
现在的问题是  你打算怎么做呢
the question is, what are you gonna do about it?
笑什么呢
What's so funny?
我在想那个白痴
I was just thinking about that nutbag.
谁会那样跟人会面
Who starts a meeting off like that?
是啊  不过还是值得夸奖
Yeah, you got to give him credit, though.
多有意思啊
It was pretty fun.
你觉得他跟债权人也会玩这套吗
You think he's gonna do that bit with the creditors?
只要他肯收购债务
I don't care
就算他让他们把乳液往篮子里放
if he makes them put the lotion in the basket,
我也不在乎
as long as he buys up their debt.
不然又得用水冲[《沉默的羔羊》台词]
Or else it gets the hose again.
等一下  她是不是身材肥胖[台词]
Wait, was she a great big fat person?
今天干得漂亮  迈克
Good job today, Mike.
谢谢
Thanks.
这是不是意味着我争取到了
Does this mean I've earned the right
跟你聊聊唐娜事件的权利
for us to talk about the Donna situation?
没有什么唐娜事件
There is no Donna situation.
得了  我知道你不是感性的人  但是
Harvey, come on, I know you're not touchy-feely, but--
听着  没什么好聊的
Look, there's nothing to talk about,
因为这种情况不会长久
because it isn't gonna last.
好吧
Okay.
烤箱里有乔治亚的外卖  我重新热了
I got some Georgio's reheating in the oven.
你真是我的大救星
Oh, you are my hero.
我知道
Oh, I know.
谁说男人不会下厨了
I mean, who says that men can't cook?
我猜是乔治亚说的
I think Georgio's does.
这个观点很正确
That's a fair point.
你的考试怎么样了
So how was your test?
有那么差吗
Whoa, it was that bad?
你都学疯了
You studied like crazy.
不  不是考得差
No, it's not that it was that bad.
而是
I just...
我没去考
I didn't take it.
你说没考是什么意思
What do you mean you didn't take it?
我决定熬夜帮哈维
I decided to stay late and help Harvey.
帮哈维干什么
Help Harvey what?
算了  我知道干什么
Never mind. I know what.
肯定是唐娜的工作
Something that would've been done by Donna
应该由他的新秘书做
and should've been done by his new secretary
但他还没有雇新的
except he hasn't hired one yet.
是你说我们应该尽可能地
You're the one who said we should cut him as much slack
体谅他
as he needs.
我是说容忍他的混蛋行径
I meant tolerating him being a dick.
可不是让你逃学
Not you flunking out of school.
上次我向哈维要求放假
The last time I asked Harvey for time off,
他告诉我说  工作就是我的法学课
he told me work is my law school,
而他是对的
and he was right.
我不会在他最需要我的时候要求休息
I'm not gonna ask him for time when he needs me the most.
怎么了
What?
-怎么了  -我只是想到
- What? - I was just thinking about
当我向你求婚的时候
when I asked you to marry me,
我说  你是那么坚强
I said how tenacious you are.
我知道
Well, I know.
你该知道自己爱上的是什么样的人
It's like you should know what you're getting yourself into.
但你知道你不戴戒指
But you see what happens when you don't wear that collar
-会发生什么吗  -闭嘴
- on your finger? - Stop it.
简直不能相信  你真的属于我了
I can't believe you're really mine.
那么  放哪里比较好呢
Now, where would be the perfect place to...
早上好  路易
Good morning, Louis.
老天  我都被你吓尿了
Holy shit. You just scared the shit out of me.
你怎么来的这么早
What are you doing here so early?
已经八点十五分了
It's 8:15.
没错  但昨晚我们工作到很晚
Well, yeah, but we worked late last night,
我让你今天上午休息一下
and I told you to take the morning.
路易  我才来第二天  我不会休息的
Louis, it's day two, I'm not taking anything.
该死
Oh, shoot.
我懂了
I get it.
你来得早是因为你给我买了
You came in early because you bought me
很贵重的礼物  而且你想
an expensive gift and you wanted to
放在我桌上  让我惊喜
surprise me by putting it on my desk.
差不多吧
Something like that.
你想让我走开吗  这样就可以给我惊喜了
Do you want me to go? You can still surprise me.
还是算了
Never mind.
鉴于你已经来了
Uh... Being that you're here,
有个潜在客户九点会来
I have a prospective client coming in at 9:00.
不会来了
No, you don't.
什么意思  那混蛋取消了约会
What do you mean? The asshole canceled?
不  那混蛋故意提前了一小时  来过了
No, the asshole intentionally showed up an hour early
我让他回家了  让他一小时后再来
and I sent him home, telling him he was an hour late.
什么  你疯了吗
What, are you crazy?
那可是卡尔・菲尔茨  唐娜
That was Carl Fields, Donna.
没准能赚他一千二百万  你却让他回去了
$12 million in billings you let walk out the door.
不  一千二百万已经到手
No, that's 12 million in billings that's coming your way
因为现在他知道你不会随他摆布
because now he knows you're not someone to be trifled with.
不  你怎么知道
No, you can't know that.
是吗  因为我刚刚接到
Really? Because I just got off the phone
他秘书打来的电话  他们希望你能一小时后
with his secretary, and they're expecting you to come by
带着委托书过去一趟
with an engagement letter in an hour.
不是吧
Holy shit!
-该死  -怎么了
- Oh, shit. - What?
什么问题
What's the problem?
我还在用旧打印机打印
I'm still printing to my old printer.
什么  打印委托书吗
What, for the engagement letter?
唐娜  拜托  你做得够多了
Donna, please, you've done enough.
我过去拿就好
Let me take care of it.
以为我没注意到吗
Like I wouldn't notice.
这是才你的位置  小东西
There you go, little fella.
我  我只是
I was, I was just...
没事  路易  不管你在干什么
It's fine, Louis. Whatever you were doing,
-没事的  -哈维
- it's fine. - Hey, Harvey,
如果你对唐娜的事有任何不愉快...
if there are any hard feelings with Donna...
不  路易  没有不愉快
No, Louis. No hard feelings.
但我只想说  如果万一有...
Okay, but I just want to say, if there was...
我说了  没有
I said there's no hard feelings.
既然说到这
As a matter of fact,
帮我告诉唐娜  我让她拿走这个
why don't you tell Donna I want her to have this?
路易的秘书候选名单
她要抛弃你了
She's leaving you.
你想见我
You wanted to see me?
那是一小时前的事了
That was an hour ago.
我刚刚听说
Well, I just heard.
而我刚刚听说你和迈克的
And I just heard the results
小小强硬策略
of your little strong-arm tactic with Mike.
你是说  你听说那办法行得通
You mean you heard that it worked.
我知道你逼迫他们照你希望做事了
Oh, I know you got them to do what you wanted.
他们欺压了所有其他债权人
They bullied all the other creditors,
买了他们所有的债务
bought off all their debt,
而且他们会等待八个星期
and they're going to back off for eight weeks.
为什么你看起来有点生气
Why do you seem pissed?
因为你的名单上  少了一个债权人
Because you left a creditor off the list.
什么  怎么可能
What? How could that happen?
我不知为什么会出这种事
I don't know how it happened,
但我知道这意味着什么
but I know what it means.
他们会用这个来要挟我们的
We're gonna get held hostage.
我会处理的
I'll take care of it.
而如果你处理不了  斯莱特里真的破产了
And if you can't take care of it and Slattery goes bankrupt,
你最好能想出办法把他留住
you better figure out a way to keep him here.
这是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
意思是杰克・索罗夫正在律所里到处说
It means Jack Soloff's been going around the firm
你不可能挽救那家公司
saying you're never gonna save that company
而如果你真的不成功  我们也没有计划
and we don't have a plan to retain their business
能留住他们
when you don't.
你什么时候开始在乎杰克・索罗夫说什么了
Since when do you care about what Jack Soloff says?
自从他成了一个有野心的资深合伙人
Since he's a senior partner with ambition
而你在两天之内失误了两次
and you dropped the ball twice in the two days.
如果你这么害怕他  干吗不直接炒了他
If you're so afraid of him, why don't you just fire him?
我不害怕任何人
I'm not afraid of anybody,
我也从没说过有野心是坏事
and I never said ambition was a bad thing.
-杰西卡  -哈维
- Jessica-- - Harvey,
我不知道你和唐娜之间是怎么回事
I don't know what's going on between you and Donna,
但我知道你选择不用我参与这件事
but I do know you chose not to let me in on it,
所以我就让你自己处理
so I'm gonna let you in on this.
如果想不出没有她怎么好好工作
If you can't figure out how to get shit done
我可就要想办法了
without her, I will.
和菲尔茨先生的会面怎么样
How'd it go with Mr. Fields?
还行  不过在你拍断胳膊
Fine, but before you dislocate your arm
夸自己做得很好之前
patting yourself on the back,
我需要你今天离开前把这些归档
I need you to file those before you leave today.
全都要吗
All of them?
是的  全都要  "这些"就是全部的意思
Yes, all of them. That's what "those" means.
还有  明早前把我的办公软件升级好
And then I want you to update my Word Perfect by the morning.
路易  我买了剧院八点场的票
Louis, I have tickets to the theater at 8:00.
刚工作第二天你就绝不加班吗
Second day and you're already taking banking hours?
好吧  我可不认为八点算是...
Okay, I hardly think 8:00 constitutes--
诺玛全年无休地每天工作到深夜
Norma worked till midnight eight days a week
还从没嘟囔过
and never bunted an eye.
-嘟囔  -对  嘟囔
- Bunted? - Yes, bunted.
你现在对我用词也有意见了吗
You have a problem with my words now?
好吧  路易  我不知道
Okay, Louis, I don't know
你是漏喝你的美容饮料了还是怎么着
if you skipped your afternoon prunie or what,
但你现在让我非常不舒服
but you're making me feel uncomfortable.
那咱们就把话说清楚
Well, let's get something straight.
我不是来让你的生活变舒服的
I'm not here to make your life comfortable.
应该是你让我的生活变舒服
You're here to do that for me.
还有下次你再用错误的打印机打了东西
And the next time you print something to the wrong copier,
你自己去拿
get it yourself.
我就给了你一项任务  找到斯莱特里
I gave you one job-- to find every single one
所有的债权人  然后你还搞砸了
of Slattery's creditors, and you screwed it up.
-你在说什么  -你漏了一个
- What are you talking about? - You left one off the list,
等他们意识到
and as soon as they realize
我们买断了其他所有人的债权
that we bought out everyone else,
他们就会知道我们达成了协议
they'll know we have a deal
然后他们就会申报债权
and they'll call in their debt
然后整个事情就全完了
and the whole thing will blow up.
等等  他们还没申报债权吗
Wait a second, they haven't even called it in yet?
没有  当然还没有
No, they haven't called it in yet,
因为他们会等到最后一刻
because they're gonna wait till the last second
那样他们就可以任意摆布我们了
so they can hold us over a barrel
就因为你没做好你的工作
because you didn't do your job.
现在我得去找能制衡凯森金融公司的筹码了
And now I gotta find some leverage on Katzen Financial.
我没有漏掉凯森金融公司
I didn't miss Katzen Financial.
那为什么他们不再单子上
Then why weren't they on the list?
我不知道  他们明明就在单子上  我给了
I don't know, they were on the list when I sent it--
见鬼  瑞秋
Goddamn Rachel.
哈维
Harvey!
凯森是单子上最后一家
Katzen was the last name on that list
而且是最后一页上唯一一家  好吗
and the only name on that page, all right?
肯定是打印机没纸了
The printer must have just run out of paper.
这不是瑞秋的错
This isn't Rachel's fault.
那我要怎么和凯文・斯莱特里说
What am I supposed to tell Kevin Slattery?
"你失去你的公司是因为
"The reason you're losing your company
我的助理律师没给打印机装纸吗"
is because my associate didn't load the printer"?
我不知道  为什么不告诉他真相
I don't know, how about you tell him the truth?
他可能失去他公司的原因
That the reason he may lose his company
是你不肯雇个新秘书
is because you didn't hire a secretary.
这话什么意思
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
你知道什么意思
You know what it means.
瑞秋一直在拼了命地照顾你
Rachel has been killing herself to take care of you,
而我们什么都没说
and we haven't said anything
就因为我们俩都同意要体谅你
because we both agreed to cut you some slack.
-我们  -是的  我们
- We? - Yeah, we,
但我不能让你因为搞砸了一件
but I'm not gonna let you come down on her
本来就不是她工作的事而训斥她
for screwing up something that wasn't her job.
她的工作就是照我说的去做
Her job is to do what I say,
你最好意识到这一点
and you better wrap your head around that.
不  哈维  你最好意识到唐娜已经走了
No, Harvey you better wrap your head around the fact
而且她不会再回来了这个事实
that Donna is gone and she is not coming back.
我告诉过你  她和路易之间不会长久的
And I told you, it's not gonna last with her and Louis.
你坚持这样说
You keep saying that,
可我眼见唐娜坐在路易的办公室外
but all I see is donna outside Louis's office
而你办公室外却空无一人
and no one outside yours.
所以你最好放下身段去请她帮忙
So you better swallow your pride and ask her for help,
或者雇个新秘书  反正不管怎么样
or hire a new secretary, but either way,
你不能拿瑞秋撒气
you're done taking it out on Rachel.
你有时间吗
Hey, there, you got a minute?
几乎没有
Barely.
我需要你之前跟我说的那两个星期
I need those two weeks you offered me before.
恐怕现在说太晚了
I'm afraid it's too late for that.
唐娜  我快完蛋了
Donna, I'm drowning.
斯莱特里这个案子...
This whole thing with the Slattery deal is--
对于你的案子我很遗憾  哈维
I'm sorry about your deal, Harvey,
但你当初拒绝我前就该想到这一点
but you should have thought about that before you turned me down.
所以你在惩罚我吗
So you're punishing me?
我没有惩罚你
I'm not punishing you.
可我自己的活都堆积如山  就算没有
But I have a mountain of work, and even if I didn't,
如果我突然又开始为你做事了
how do you think Louis would feel if I suddenly
你觉得路易会怎么想
started working for you again?
我才不管路易怎么想
I don't give a shit how Louis feels.
那你考虑过我的感受吗
Well, what about how I feel?
你现在又在动摇我的心意
Which is that you're trying to undermine my decision.
我怎么能动摇你的心意呢
How the hell am I trying to undermine your decision?
那这个算什么
What do you call this?
那是之前...
That--that was before--
什么之前  在你碰到路易之前
Before what? Before you ran into Louis?
在你需要我的帮助之前  什么之前
Before you needed my help? What?
唐娜
Donna--
你知道我在哪里找到的吗
Do you know where I found this?
出于关心我还留着那份秘书候选名单
Louis put it right on top of the list of secretaries
而路易恰恰把它放在了那份名单上
that I have been keeping for you because I still care about you,
你知道这两件事共同的结果是什么
and you know what they both did?
刚好触发了他的噩梦
They fed right into his nightmare
让他觉得我要离开他
that I'm gonna leave him,
而这就是你想要的结果
which is exactly what you wanted.
你知道要我放下身段
Do you know how hard it is for me
到这里来找你有多难吗
to swallow my pride and come over here?
那你知道要我拒绝你又有多难吗
Do you know how hard it is for me to say no to you?
那就别拒绝
Then don't.
我只是要你帮我做一件小事
I am asking you for one little thing.
不  哈维  不是一件小事
No, Harvey, it's not one little thing.
今天是斯莱特里收购案
Today it's the Slattery deal,
明天是韦斯合并案
tomorrow's the Weiss merger,
而后天
and then the day after that,
就会是成千上万其他事情
it will be a million other things
直到你觉得一切恢复原样了
until you think everything is back to normal.
但回不去了  这就是新常态
Well, it's not. This is the new normal.
现在我的办公桌在这  对你我爱莫能助
This is my desk now, and I wish I could help you, but I can't.
唐娜  别这样
Donna, please.
抱歉  哈维  你得靠自己了
I'm sorry, Harvey, you're on your own.
就在那一刻  对吧
And that's when it happened, isn't it?
你的恐慌症又发作了
You had another one.
我不...不想谈了
I don't--I don't want to talk about it.
要解决问题第一步就是不回避
Step one to making them stop is talking about it.
我无法思考  也看不见  我...
I couldn't think, I couldn't see, I c--
不能呼吸
I couldn't breath.
然后你做了什么
And what did you do?
你明知故问
You know what I did.
对  但我要你说出来
No, I know. I need you to say it.
为什么
Why?
因为说得越多  它对你的影响就越小
'Cause the more you say it, the less power it has over you.
我走进洗手间
I made my way into the bathroom,
我听见心脏剧烈跳动  然后
and my heart was p-pounding, and
我的胸要炸开了
my chest cracked open.
就像...就像我溺水了一样
It was--it was like I was under water.
我看着隔间  那有两只鞋
I looked at the stall, and there was...two shoes there,
屎色棕的鞋  没系鞋带  两个人在笑
a piece-of-shit brown shoe, untied, two guys laugh--
好的  然后呢
Yeah, and then?
我冲进隔间  开始呕吐
I ran to the stall, I threw up,
然后我就待在那里  直到那种感觉结束
and I just waited until it was over.
那天晚上你就来找我了
And that's the night you came to see me.
没错
Yeah.
还编了一个睡眠障碍的谎话
And you made up a story about having trouble sleeping
来骗我开抗焦虑药
to get antianxiety medication,
从那之后你就每天吃一粒
and you've been taking a pill a day since.
没错
Yes.
在忙
Busy.
路易
Louis...
我没有要离开你
I'm not leaving you.
上面写着"路易的秘书候选名单"
It says, "Replacements for Louis"
那上面就这么写着"路易的秘书候选名单"
Right here on top, "Replacements for Louis."
因为那是诺玛死后我做的
That's because that's the list I made after Norma died.
那你为什么还留着
Then why do you still have it?
我留着给哈维的
Because I was saving it for Harvey.
这是给哈维的
This is for Harvey?
对  路易  因为我现在替你做事了
Yes, Louis, because I work for you now,
我想告诉你别再怀疑
and I'd like to tell you to stop questioning
我是否会改变心意了
whether I'm gonna change my mind,
我们都知道这不可能
but we both know that's never gonna happen,
所以我想说...
so instead, I'll say...
如果你怀疑我就直接告诉我
you need to talk to me about it when it does.
我告诉过你啊  唐娜
But I did talk to you, Donna.
我先是加大你的工作量  然后吼你
First, I loaded you up with work, then I yelled at you,
后来还把开罐器放在名单上面
and then I put the can-opener on top of that list.
我不能再直接了
I mean, I can't be more direct than that.
可以的  路易
Yes, you can, Louis.
我不想再有任何不坦诚的关系了
Because I don't want that kind of relationship anymore.
那是做什么用的
What's it for?
什么是做什么用的
What's what for?
那个开罐器
The can opener.
就是一个开罐器  路易
It's just a can opener, Louis.
不  没那么简单
No, it's not.
哈维给我的时候想传达某种信息
Harvey was sending me a message when he gave it to me.
那个信息不是给你的
That message wasn't meant for you.
是要传达给我的
It was meant for me.
唐娜  你要我开诚布公
Donna, you want me to talk to you,
但你现在却含糊其辞
but now you're not talking to me.
那是哈维和我在每次出庭前
It was a ritual that Harvey and I would do
都会有的一个仪式
before we went to trial.
所以他想表达的意思是
So the message was,
唐娜  你和我就永远不会有那样的仪式
Donna, you'll never have something like that with me.
不  路易  不是那样
No, Louis, that's not what--
我们该有一个仪式
We should have a ritual.
等我们赢下第一件大案子再考虑吧
Let's worry about that after we win our first big case.
我本来还想请你喝一杯呢
I was just about to offer you one of those.
杰西卡  如果你是来再骂我一通的话
Jessica, if you're here to yell at me again--
我不是来吼你的
I'm not here to yell at you.
我是来跟你道歉的
I'm here to apologize to you.
那就一起喝一杯吧
Then you can have a drink.
事实上  一个好的合伙人知道这其中的区别
The truth is, there's a time for yelling
既要有骂人的时候
and there is a time for understanding,
也要有理解人的时候
and a good partner knows the difference.
你是指一个好的管理合伙人吧
You mean a good managing partner.
不  就是好的合伙人
No, I mean a good partner.
那晚你发现唐娜有麻烦了
The night you found out Donna was in trouble,
但你做的第一件事  却是挤了时间
the first thing you did was take the time...
和我喝一杯  聊了杰夫
to have a drink with me about Jeff.
所以  至少我能花点时间
So the least I could do is take the time
来理解你的情况
and understand your situation.
你是指  我已经没有秘书的事实吗
You mean, the fact that I don't have a secretary.
我是指  你一定要打包一起来工作的女人
I mean that after 12 years, the woman you wouldn't
十二年后  却在为别人做事
come work here without is now working for someone else.
所以你想知道原因
And you want to know why.
我不用知道原因
I don't need to know why.
我要知道你想不想让我帮你恢复原状
I need to know if you want me to undo it.
什么
What?
我知道你和唐娜不像我跟杰夫
I know you and Donna aren't me and Jeff,
但是你们俩的亲密无间
but you are as close as two people can be
不是恋人胜似恋人
without being that.
该死  哈维  斯科特走的时候
Shit, Harvey, Scottie leaving
你都没这么受打击颓废过
didn't throw you off your game this much.
谢谢你的好意
I appreciate the offer.
但只要唐娜想为路易工作
But as long as Donna wants to work for Louis,
我就不会强迫她再回来为我做事
I am not gonna force her to work for me.
好吧
Okay.
哈维  你有没有想过
Harvey, have you thought about
要是唐娜真的不回来了怎么办
what's going to happen if she doesn't come back?
她会回来的
She will.
哇
Wow.
哇什么
Wow what?
杰西卡听着真是个女中豪杰
This Jessica sounds like a hell of a woman.
这跟我说的事有什么关系
What does that have to do with anything?
没什么关系  我  我只是
No, it doesn't. I-I was just--
我不管你在干嘛
Look, I don't care what you were doing.
我们已经待得够久了
We've been here long enough.
是的
Hmm, we have.
但我不会给你另外开药了
But I'm not gonna give you another prescription.
你说要是我敞开心扉
You said if I opened up--
我说要是你不敞  我就不开
I said if you didn't, I wouldn't.
我可没说你敞了我就会开啊
I didn't say if you did, I would.
这可不是一回事
They're not the same thing.
该死
Goddamn it.
等等  你听我把话说完
Hold on, you didn't let me finish.
我不会再给你另开药
I'm not gonna write you another prescription.
但给你这个
I'm gonna give you these.
够你吃一周的了
That's enough for another week.
你想让我下次再来
You want me to come in here again.
当然
Mm, I sure do.
你也可以摇着骰子慢慢吃
Or you can roll the dice and spread them out,
但你不再来我这儿就拿不到新的
but you're not getting anymore without seeing me again.
还有
One more thing.
恐慌症会一直发作
These episodes are gonna keep happening
直到你接受唐娜有可能再也不会回来的现实
until you accept the fact that Donna may never come back.
你整个早上都去哪儿了
Where the hell have you been all morning?
你是我什么人  老妈吗
What are you, my mother?
我去开会了  怎么了
I was at a meeting. Why?
还记得你说凯森要
Remember when you said Katzen was gonna
等到最后一秒让我们不得翻身吗
wait till the last second to hold us over a barrel?
可是他们没有  他们把所有的债务
Well, they didn't. They sold all of their debt
卖给了凯文・斯莱特里最强的竞争对手
to Kevin Slattery's biggest competitor.
他们想把我们一击击倒  一劳永逸
They're gonna want to put us in the ground for good.
那幸好我已经想出办法
Well, then it's a good thing I figured out a way
说服他们别这么干了
to convince 'em not to.
那我们还傻站在这儿干嘛
What the hell are we still doing here?
你说呢
You tell me.
到底是怎么回事
What the hell happened?
大西洋货运公司是我的主要对手
Atlantic Freight is my chief rival.
如果他们要收回债务
If they call in the debt,
他们会强制宣告我破产的
they'll force me into bankruptcy.
前提是他们要收回债务
If they call in the debt.
他什么意思
What is he talking about?
他的意思是  我们刚和他们开了个会
He's talking about the fact that we just came from a meeting with them,
并且你是对的
and you're right.
对他们来说  把你彻底击倒  一劳永逸
They'd love nothing more than to put you down
是最好不过了
once and for all.
他妈的
Goddamn it.
但好消息是  我们告诉他们
But lucky for you, we told them
如果他们迫使你破产
that if they force you into bankruptcy,
那未必会搞垮你的公司
that doesn't necessarily kill your company,
但买下你的冠名权会
but buying your name does.
所以我现在归他们了  这就是你的天才方案
So they own me? That's your brilliant solution?
不是  他们有的是斯莱特里的商标
No, they own the Slattery trademark,
并且认为这是打垮你的最有效方法
which they think effectively puts you under,
但是他们不知道我们知道的事
but they don't know what we know.
你们知道什么
And what is that?
你还有另外一份合同
That you have another contract
这份合同不管你公司的名称
that doesn't care about the name of your company.
他们只在乎所有者的名称
They only care about the name of the owner.
凯森是怎么知道要卖债权的
How the hell did Katzen even know to sell their debt?
因为我失误了
Because I made a mistake.
妈的你是失误了
You sure as hell did!
你要了我公司20%的股份
After asking for 20% of my company
还夸下海口说你能救下它
and bragging that you could save it.
结果却证明  你只是个自大的说嘴货
Well, it turns out it, you're just an arrogant mouthpiece
觉得自己能拯救一切
that thinks he can save anything.
但其实你做不到
But you can't.
凯文  没人比我更讨厌改变
Kevin, nobody hates change more than I do,
但无论你是否喜欢  改变都会发生
but it's coming whether we like it or not.
如果我可以同时拯救你的公司和你的冠名
And if I could save both your company and your name,
我会  但你说对了  我做不到
I would, but you're right, I can't.
所以接受交易吧  明天醒来  去上班
So take the deal, wake up tomorrow, and go to work.
哈维
Hey, Harvey?
怎么
Yeah.
我只想说谢谢
I just want to say thanks...
谢谢你没让我们承担责任
for not throwing us under the bus back there.
什么意思
What do you mean?
你本可以告诉凯文・斯莱特里实话
Well, I mean, you could have told Kevin Slattery the truth.
错误是我和瑞秋犯下的
That mistake was mine and Rachel's.
不  不是
No it wasn't.
你之前说对了  是我的错
You were right, that mistake was mine.
你这么晚在这儿干嘛
Hey. What are you doing here so late?
你没听说吗
You didn't hear?
戴维斯兄弟的案子解决了
We closed the Davis brothers.
-那可是大事  -是的
- That's huge. - It is.
我在想这可能是个绝佳的时机
So I thought maybe this was the perfect time
来建立我们的仪式
to start our ritual.
唐娜  我在想
Oh, Donna, listen, I've been thinking.
我们或许不需要仪式
I don't think we need to have a ritual.
来吧  这是我们第一个大胜利
Come on. It's our first big win.
跟我给迈克的蛋糕一模一样
That's the same exact cake I got Mike.
我知道
I know.
你怎么知道的
How did you know?
我可是唐娜
I'm Donna.
你确实是
You sure are.
什么口味的
What flavor is it?
我打电话给埃斯特  她说
Well, I called Esther, and she said
你最爱是德国巧克力味
German Chocolate was your favorite.
我讨厌德国巧克力
I hate German Chocolate.
所以我买了摩卡软糖味
Which is why I got you Mocha Fudge.
完美
It's perfect.
有什么事吗  哈维
What can I do for you, Harvey?
我想看看那个名单还在不在你这里
I just wanted to see if you still had that list.
当然在
Of course I do.
这是什么
What's this?
你的订婚礼物
Your engagement present.
拜托  瑞秋  你觉得
Come on, Rachel, how long did you think
你浑身那光芒还能藏多久
you could keep that glow a secret?
我有光芒
I'm glowing?
跟除夕夜的时代广场一样亮
Like Times Square on New Year's Eve.
在我看来
To me.
世界其他人都没法
The rest of the world can't even see you
在你担下的大堆哈维的工作底下看到你
under that pile of work you took on to help Harvey.
你还知道那个
You knew about that too?
我当然知道
Of course I did,
所以你得到了这个
which is why you're getting this.
唐娜  你不用...
Donna, you didn't have to--
我是不用  但哈维需要
I didn't, but Harvey did.
但他不会想到要送你俩礼物
And he won't think to get you two a gift,
因为平时都是我
'cause I was always the one
来搞定这种事的  所以...
who took care of things like that, so...
我不知道说什么好了
I don't know what to say.
说谢谢就可以
Say thank you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
然后跟我保证
And promise me,
不管我生活中发生什么事
no matter what is going on in my life,
你都不会为跟我说你的好消息而不好意思
you won't feel bad about telling me all the good things in yours.
我保证
I promise.
这是什么
What is this?
一本《新娘》杂志
A copy of Brides Magazine.
放我桌上干嘛
Why is it on my desk?
不然你们要怎么选颜色
How else are you gonna pick your colors?
选颜色
Colors？
选什么颜色
What are colors?
你怎么会懂这些
How do you know what they are?
因为我是个成年男人
Because I'm a grown man.
是吗  可你听着更像个成年女性啊
Really? 'Cause you sound more like a grown woman.
这话很伤人
That's very hurtful.
我到处找才找到的
I looked everywhere for that issue.
谢谢  哈维
Thanks, Harvey.
路上再谢吧
Thank me on the way.
我们要去哪
Where are we going?
去办你订婚当天就该办的事
To do what we should have done the day you got engaged.
去看篮球赛
Nets game.
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding?
第一排哦
Front row.
我的老天
Holy shit.
Jay-Z会去吗
Is Jay-Z gonna be there?
会呀  他座位就在我旁边
Yeah, right next to me.
你旁边  等等  这是给我的礼物
Next to you? Wait, this my gift, hey?
我不管是谁的礼物  我不能残忍地让Jay-Z挨着你
I don't care whose gift it is. I'm not doing that to Jay-Z.
好吧  我坐碧昂丝旁边算了
Oh, you know what, I'll just sit next to Beyonc.
就算我们扯平了
We'll call it a draw.
得了  不用想了
You know what, never mind.
我带瑞秋去
I'm taking Rachel.
是吗  你不如把票给我俩算了
Yeah, well, why don't you just give it to both of us?
等等  那谁留在这儿做你的工作呢
Oh, wait, then who would stay here and do all your work?
要命  玩笑开太早了吗
Shit. Was that too soon?
抱歉  兄弟  我们走
Oh, I'm so sorry, bud. Let's go!